WAYNE LAMBERT

Edgbaston, Birmingham, UK

contact@waynelambert.dev | +44 (0)7950 315504

An innovative business applications developer with over 15 years' experience managing the design, development, and delivery of effective, intuitive, and user-friendly solutions.

Engages clients and senior managers providing project updates and specialist product guidance. Enjoys collaborating in teams to develop applications and transform outcomes using Agile methodologies.

KEY SKILLS

Programming: Algorithms, data structures, design patterns, coding, debugging, testing, logging, UX

Languages: Python, HTML / CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, JSX, SQL, Unix shell scripting, VBA

Frameworks: Django, Django REST, Flask, React.js, Node / Express.js, Bootstrap, Ant

Developer Tools: VS Code, PyCharm, iTerm, GitHub, Docker, Firefox Dev Tools, DataGrip, Paw, Linux, AWS

Databases: PostgreSQL, SQLite3, MySQL, SQL Server, Oracle

PROFESSIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

- **Designed and developed comprehensive web portfolio:** Built using latest web technologies including Django, Django REST, Python, JavaScript, GitHub, Docker, Postgres, HTML / CSS, and Bootstrap.
- Developed tools contributing to save an estimated €80m: Designed and developed a comprehensive suite of VBA tools using Agile methodologies. Implemented fixed pay target ranges across cost base of €4.8bn, assignment of inbound team emails using operational logic, and delivered automated email communications to 40,000 employees.
- Augmented executive management compensation reporting with €2.1bn bonus pool: Facilitated global
 compensation strategy and policy for the Senior Executive Compensation Committee through interactive dashboard
 creation and key message insights.
- Managed a workstream as part of large-scale HR transformation: Managed data migration programme through ETL processes and redeveloped strategic reporting landscape using BusinessObjects Web Intelligence. SME in recruitment, lifecycle, payroll, performance, reward, and organisational effectiveness processes to outsourced services provider.
- Improved reporting efficiency and key messages/insights reporting: Improved accuracy and reporting efficiency by transforming processes previously taking over 6 days to around 1 day. This was achieved through leadership in the development and streamlining of corporate MI dashboard reporting and the introduction of QA.

CAREER HISTORY

HR BI Specialist [Ltd Co Contractor] - Deutsche Bank, Birmingham

Nov 2016 - May 2019

- Designed and developed a salary ranges VBA tool enabling employee target ranges to be cost-contained.
- Developed Access / Excel VBA solutions automating assignment of team emails and sending of email broadcasts.
- Transformed interactive dashboards and key messages insights for global Senior Executive Compensation Committee.

BI Developer & Data Migration Specialist [Ltd Co Contractor] - Admin Re UK, Telford, Shrops May 2016 - Nov 2016

- Managed comprehensive end-to-end data migration programme from existing HR administration and payroll
 providers onto single consolidated platform managing downstream system stakeholders and external consultants.
- Developed advanced VBA recruitment and data management solutions to effect robust data integrity, positive manager experiences, and streamlined operational efficiency.

HR MIS Specialist [Ltd Co Contractor] - Deutsche Bank, Birmingham

Nov 2015 - May 2016

- Co-ordinated centralised data for over 90,000 employees to implement a global Total Compensation Framework. This included the allocation of mandatory, discretionary, promotion, and PayMix shift budgetary spend.
- Managed compensation planning and employee maintenance serving as data custodian, process owner, and stakeholder manager to divisional and regional reward advisors to enable management of employee populations.
- Created system to co-ordinate over 10,000 corrections making system updates and ensuring data integrity and audit requirements were adhered to.

- Created technical data feeds solution to automate downstream business systems supporting general ledgers, business modelling, and systems and facilities access.
- Developed inputs to a data warehousing solution enabling HR and finance to align datasets for commercial analysis.
 Engagement of Strategic Change to introduce 'FTE Resource Tracker' as model owner, SME, and escalation point.
- Created a census "flight tracker" for business transformation, employee exit planning, and redundancy calculations.
- Facilitated change, project, and risk management through quality assurance and product/process reviews.

HR Systems & MI Consultant - *TATA Consultancy Services, Peterborough, Cambs*

Apr 2006 - Sep 2012

 Development and provision of MI reports as outsourced services provider for The Phoenix Group, Southern Water, and Sun Life Financial of Canada within a commercial operating environment governed by contractual SLAs and KPIs.

From 2010-2014, built and maintained an active WordPress community website reaching a consistent Alexa rank of circa 60,000. This entailed blog and video content creation, PHP modifications, AWeber email integration, Linux and MySQL database administration, Amazon S3 and CloudFront.

Consulted independently and delivered several freelance projects including designing a database schema for a Cultural Audit and Map for Dublin City Council.

Roles prior to April 2006 include Stock Controller and Production Team Leader.

SKILLS PROFILE

Data Science: Anaconda: Jupyter, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Bokeh

Business Intelligence: BusinessObjects, MS Excel, MS Access, Tableau, Oracle Query, dashboards, data visualisation **Project Management:** Agile project / product development, stakeholder engagement, risk / change management, QA

Tools / Media: WordPress, SEO, AdWords, Google Analytics, Camtasia, split testing, online media

Systems / Other: MacOS, Windows, Linux, AutoCAD, iTrent, PeopleSoft, data warehousing, ETL data migration

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Enjoys a continuous programme of self-study for professional and personal development principally targeted towards skills in software engineering, web development, data science, and business intelligence.

In addition to numerous video courses, I have studied many highly regarded books by industry leading experts in programming and web development. These include 'Clean Code', 'A Common-Sense Guide to Data Structures and Algorithms', 'Django for Professionals', 'REST APIs with Django', and 'Think Python'.

I have recently enjoyed further developing my skills at PyCon UK.

EDUCATION

Robert Manning School (now Bourne Academy) - Bourne, Lincs

Sep 1991 - Jul 1998

- GNVQ Advanced Business Studies
- 5 GCSEs at grades B C

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

My web development work can be reviewed on my portfolio website, https://waynelambert.dev, and the corresponding source code can be browsed using the 'View Code' button on the home page.

References available upon request